Global Benchmarks for World-Class Quality
Welcome back to this session on benchmarking.
What we’re looking at now is the Sigma Scale one sigma, two, three, four, and so on.
And the corresponding percentages associated with each.
So, what we’re looking at is about 1.5 Sigma is about 50% good.
2.3. Sigma is about 80% good.
90% is 2.8. 99 is about 3.8.
99.9 is about 4.6 Sigma.
99.99% good stuff is 5.2.
Three 9’s is 5.8 Sigma.
So, we can clearly see from this chart
that 99.9%, 4.6 Sigma,
is generally around best in class. World-class Five Sigma.
The typical service organization is around 2.5 Sigma,
while the target for manufacturing is about Four Sigma.
And recall that, that translates to roughly 20% of sales.
Whereas Six Sigma, or 3.4 defects per million opportunities, is less than 1% of sales.
So, this allows us to see what our competitive advantage might be
when comparing ourselves to someone else.
Remember from our previous benchmarking
We take the notion, Y is a function of X.
So, if I see something on the outcome, that's about Four Sigma.
What do you suppose I surmise about that Four Sigma?
Basically, Four Sigma in. Four Sigma out.
So, If I take Four Sigma drawings, Four Sigma managers, Four Sigma trained people,
Four Sigma suppliers. What do you suppose comes out the back end?
Twenty Sigma? I don't think so.
Trash in. Trash out. Average in. Average out.
So, this is another form of benchmarking.
Thank you for choosing SSMI.